<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Top 10 on Andy Dyer</title>
    <link>http://andydyer.org/categories/top-10/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Top 10 on Andy Dyer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2015 Copyright Andy Dyer</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2016 14:38:02 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://andydyer.org/categories/top-10/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 Albums of 2015</title>
      <link>http://andydyer.org/blog/2016/01/02/top-10-albums-of-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2016 14:38:02 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://andydyer.org/blog/2016/01/02/top-10-albums-of-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a bit late with my annual Top 10 list, but here it is roughly ranked by Google Music play count:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Earl Sweatshirt - I Don&amp;rsquo;t Like Shit, I Don&amp;rsquo;t Go Outside&lt;/strong&gt; I was finally lucky enough to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.houstonpress.com/music/earl-sweatshirt-revels-in-raps-odd-future-at-warehouse-live-7746980&#34;&gt;see him live&lt;/a&gt; and he didn&amp;rsquo;t disappoint. Another great release. This soundtracked numerous skateboard and chill sessions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vince Staples - Summertime &amp;lsquo;06&lt;/strong&gt; His &amp;ldquo;Hell Can Wait&amp;rdquo; EP made my list last year and I knew this one would be on this year&amp;rsquo;s list right away. The subject matter is heavy, but you may be nodding your head so much at first you won&amp;rsquo;t notice. I recommend multiple listens so you can fully appreciate both its depth and undeniable crunkness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Drumcode - A-Sides Volume III&lt;/strong&gt; Ever since getting bitten by the techno bug, I&amp;rsquo;ve compiled a solid list of podcasts I listen to regularly like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.droidbehavior.com/blog/podcast/&#34;&gt;Droid Podcast&lt;/a&gt; and Adam Beyer&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://drumcode.se/&#34;&gt;Drumcode Radio (DCR)&lt;/a&gt;. This collection of Drumcode singles includes many that were feature on DCR.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fuzz - II&lt;/strong&gt; This Ty Segall side project returns with another face melting set. For when you want to rock. Hard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ryan Adams - 1989&lt;/strong&gt; I had successfully avoided knowingly hearing any of Taylor Swift&amp;rsquo;s album until I heard this song-for-song cover album from the prolific Mr. Adams. Now I realize they&amp;rsquo;ve been plaguing my every shopping experience for months. But there&amp;rsquo;s no way around it, these are good songs. I contend they&amp;rsquo;re even better with Ryan Adams performing them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Panda Bear - Panda Bear Meets the Grim Reaper&lt;/strong&gt; For the uninitiated, Panda Bear is a member of Animal Collective, a pretty kick ass indie psych band. This is his fifth solo album. Reverb, chants, and a masterful combination of Eastern &amp;amp; electronic instruments pay tribute to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lD4sxxoJGkA&#34;&gt;Pet Sounds&lt;/a&gt; and beyond.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buxton - Half a Native&lt;/strong&gt; Houston&amp;rsquo;s Buxton delivers an album of honest and heartfelt songs. We&amp;rsquo;ve all been there, but when Sergio Trevino sings about shyly introducing himself to a woman in &amp;ldquo;Pool Hall&amp;rdquo;, you feel like you &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; there.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deerhunter - Fading Frontier&lt;/strong&gt; Bradford Cox and crew continue their legacy of jangly rock songs that are hard to categorize, but always sound like Deerhunter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Car Seat Headrest - Teens of Style&lt;/strong&gt; I owe this discovery to NPR All Songs Considered&amp;rsquo;s coverage of the CMJ Music Festival. The young Will Toledo&amp;rsquo;s bedroom recordings confirm he has another great album coming when he records in a proper studio in 2016.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wilco - Star Wars&lt;/strong&gt; This Wilco album came out of nowhere&amp;hellip;no press coverage, no teased release date&amp;hellip;just a free download on the interwebz. Sure, it&amp;rsquo;s another Wilco album, but one that I enjoyed a bit more than their last two.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLiOTTgupZ1CBE0OdDyg1jOfQpwr0VlbA9&#34;&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a playlist&lt;/a&gt; with one of my favorite songs from each album. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 Albums of 2014</title>
      <link>http://andydyer.org/blog/2014/12/26/top-10-albums-of-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://andydyer.org/blog/2014/12/26/top-10-albums-of-2014/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The end of another year means it&amp;rsquo;s time for the annual Top 10 Favorite Albums list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ty Segall - Manipulator&lt;/strong&gt; While not the leader in sheer track plays via my Google Play Music account, this album is perfect all the way through. It certainly spent a lot of time on my turntable as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nothing - Guilty of Everything&lt;/strong&gt; A wonderful example of the specific brand of rock music I love. Heavily &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zhxXn60Z0yk&#34;&gt;MBV&lt;/a&gt; influenced wall of sound guitars. They were almost deafeningly loud when I saw them at &lt;a href=&#34;http://fitzlivemusic.com&#34;&gt;Fitzgerald&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; over the summer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Whirr - Sway&lt;/strong&gt; One of the members of Nothing also founded Whirr. As you might expect, they have a similar sound. Similarly awesome.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sturgill Simpson - Metamodern Sounds in Country Music&lt;/strong&gt; Like a modern day &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=14ZHn_76QM0&#34;&gt;Waylon Jennings&lt;/a&gt;. While I&amp;rsquo;m not a big country fan, I can appreciate honest, heartfelt songs. These are.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spoon - They Want My Soul&lt;/strong&gt; Such a consistent band. Their sound evolves slightly with each album, yet they always sound like Spoon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meatbodies - Meatbodies&lt;/strong&gt; Ty Segall&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iDEmMyowfPU&#34;&gt;Fuzz&lt;/a&gt; band mate Chad Ubovich also helms Meatbodies. Psych rock, fuzz, reverb, etc. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DuYOMvTLoJo&#34;&gt;Thee Oh Sees&lt;/a&gt;/Ty Segall type rock n&amp;rsquo; roll.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Parquet Courts - Sunbathing Animal&lt;/strong&gt; Their slacker rock sound reminds me a bit of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lPvhKV3Yg2k&#34;&gt;Pavement&lt;/a&gt;. Simple yet catchy songs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cheatahs - Cheatahs&lt;/strong&gt; On par with the Nothing and Whirr albums on the list, more fuzzy droning shoegaze-y goodness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Schoolboy Q - Oxymoron&lt;/strong&gt; I continued exploring hip-hop this year and this album led the pack. &amp;ldquo;Los Awesome&amp;rdquo; is like a modern day &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uWbXQQG9B6c&#34;&gt;California Love&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;. &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_L2vJEb6lVE&#34;&gt;Collard Greens&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; features Kendrick Lamar and name checks Houston. And more. What else do you need?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vince Staples - Hell Can Wait&lt;/strong&gt; Vince Staples has &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BGfE-mbdmXg&#34;&gt;collaborated with Earl Sweatshirt&lt;/a&gt; (whose &amp;ldquo;Doris&amp;rdquo; album was on my list last year) and toured this year with Schoolboy Q. Apparently my ear is also finely tuned for a specific style of hip-hop. Whatever the case, this album will get your head nodding if you&amp;rsquo;re into that sort of thing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I made a YouTube playlist with one of my favorite songs from each album. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;//www.youtube.com/embed/videoseries?list=PL4Qh67kwS0G6xBXF7IgmsAR_9772oiccJ&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 Albums of 2013</title>
      <link>http://andydyer.org/blog/2013/12/22/top-10-albums-of-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://andydyer.org/blog/2013/12/22/top-10-albums-of-2013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Each year, I keep a list of albums that I find myself listening to frequently. This is the time of year when I review the list and pick my top 10. I ventured into hip-hop and electronic music a bit more this year. Psych rock and 90s style fuzz are also well represented.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UUc5y1NljXI&#34;&gt;My Bloody Valentine - MBV&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YjgEBZhsGJs&#34;&gt;Disclosure - Settle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dmpOntxlbcY&#34;&gt;Swearin&amp;rsquo; - Dust in the Gold Sack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5eHoKMZf8M0&#34;&gt;Weed - Deserve&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WLsq8zPvloY&#34;&gt;Thee Oh Sees - Floating Coffin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=TPCtrybEt8E&#34;&gt;Night Beats - Sonic Bloom&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xfsXK9Lgitk&#34;&gt;Speedy Ortiz - Major Arcana&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rGEx8SfI540&#34;&gt;Unknown Mortal Orchestra - II&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dg0yfie121E&#34;&gt;Waxahatchee - Cerulean Salt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FCbWLSZrZfw&#34;&gt;Earl Sweatshirt - Doris&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>