<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Phones on </title>
    <link>http://andydyer.org/categories/phones/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Phones on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2015 Copyright Andy Dyer</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://andydyer.org/categories/phones/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I&#39;m Unironically Carrying This Small, Older Android Phone</title>
      <link>http://andydyer.org/blog/2015/02/19/why-im-unironically-carrying-this-small-older-android-phone/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://andydyer.org/blog/2015/02/19/why-im-unironically-carrying-this-small-older-android-phone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I thoroughly enjoyed my last night in Berlin a little over a week ago; so much that I didn&amp;rsquo;t notice my phone was missing until the end of the night. Shake your head and say it couldn&amp;rsquo;t happen to you. I thought the same thing until it did. Normally, I keep my phone in one of my front pockets, but I was wearing a coat that covered the pocket, making it a bit more difficult to grab my phone quickly to check Google Maps. Since my coat has a side access pocket in the chest, I stowed my phone there while walking around. I&amp;rsquo;m guessing a skillful thief at the last bar spotted my phone in that side pocket and was able to slide it out without me knowing. I was in a crowded room and often looking to one side as I talked to different people. Self-shaming thoughts aside, sometimes it happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pro Tip: When traveling abroad, keep your main SIM card with your luggage at your hotel/rental. Buy a local SIM if possible for faster data. Losing my phone but not my main SIM card made a bad situation a bit better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I noticed my phone was missing, I faced all manner of unusual challenges. Did I remember the address of my AirBnB flat? How will I wake up on time for my train in the morning without an alarm? How will I get to the train station? Luckily I was able to get back to the flat without a problem. I did wake up too late for my train the next morning, but had no problem navigating to the train station after checking the route on my laptop before leaving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I arrived at the train station and learned that there was another train a couple hours later. Not bad. This gave me time to grab a flat white &amp;amp; croissant and then do some phone shopping. With the self-shaming level still high, I decided I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to spend more than 200€ on a (possibly temporary) replacement. At that price level, a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.samsung.com/uk/consumer/mobile-devices/smartphones/android/GT-I9195ZKABTU&#34;&gt;Samsung Galaxy S4 Mini&lt;/a&gt; was pretty much my only choice. It shipped with KitKat (4.4.2) and withholding &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.androidpolice.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/02/nexusae0_182.png&#34;&gt;Samsung&amp;rsquo;s TouchWiz UI nonsense&lt;/a&gt;, it&amp;rsquo;s proven to be a pretty decent little phone. Installing the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cyanogenmod.org/&#34;&gt;CyanogenMod&lt;/a&gt; 12 ROM got me a stock Android UI and that &lt;a href=&#34;http://andydyer.org/images/lollipop.jpg&#34;&gt;sweet, sweet Lollipop&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more technically savvy among you may ask whether I was able to track my device using the Android Device Manager. This is all it&amp;rsquo;s shown for the past week:
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://andydyer.org/images/android_device_manager.png&#34; alt=&#34;Android Device Manager&#34; style=&#34;width: 827px; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto; display: block&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
After carrying the S4 Mini for a week, I&amp;rsquo;ve realized a few things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I miss small phones. I don&amp;rsquo;t need a phone with a five inch screen for most things. I have an Android Wear watch, so a large portion of my interaction with my phone occurs via my wrist anyway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Doing Android development on a flagship phone blinds us to what most of our users (even more so for global apps) are experiencing. Who has phones that old/small/underpowered? Most people.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paraphrasing &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4YMNth3JF0M&#34;&gt;Tyler Durden&lt;/a&gt;, &amp;ldquo;You are not your smart phone.&amp;rdquo; Who cares what phone you have. A more interesting question is, &amp;ldquo;What do you do with it?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why am I &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wiktionary.org/wiki/unironically&#34;&gt;unironically&lt;/a&gt; carrying this small, older Android phone? I think it will help me build better apps. And it may annoy me just enough to spend less time on my phone and more time experiencing the world around me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>