<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Have A Holly Jolly Christmas on Andy Dyer</title>
    <link>http://andydyer.org/categories/have-a-holly-jolly-christmas/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Have A Holly Jolly Christmas on Andy Dyer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2015 Copyright Andy Dyer</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://andydyer.org/categories/have-a-holly-jolly-christmas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Things To Do While I&#39;m on Vacation in December</title>
      <link>http://andydyer.org/blog/2010/11/22/things-to-do-while-im-on-vacation-in-december/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://andydyer.org/blog/2010/11/22/things-to-do-while-im-on-vacation-in-december/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#39;post&#39;&gt;
I didn&#39;t take much of my vacation time this year, so I&#39;m left with thirteen days of vacation to take in December.  In an effort to make the most of this bounty of time off, I made a list of things to do.  Thanks to Jamie for suggesting I make a list after patiently enduring my first couple brainstorming sessions.&lt;div&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;Here&#39;s the list in no particular order:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Triumphant return to homebrewing - &lt;/b&gt;Brew an American Pale Ale. Cascade hops and more Cascade hops.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#34;Fixing a hole where the rain gets in...&#34; - &lt;/b&gt;Patch a couple small leaks in the garage roof.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;No clever way to say it - &lt;/b&gt;Rake some leaves.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Dining reconnaissance at Stella Sola - &lt;/b&gt;One of the few local restaurants I haven&#39;t tried yet.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Mini &#34;Into the Wild&#34; camping trip - &lt;/b&gt;Solo camping for a few days with my guitar and mountain bike.  Maybe Huntsville State Park.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;These are the (An)droids you&#39;re looking for - &lt;/b&gt;Finally finish developing the Android application I&#39;ve been working on sporadically over the past several months.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Save me from my phone, Phone - &lt;/b&gt;Build a Windows Phone 7 equivalent of my Android application.  Given the far superior development tools available for WP7, this should be a much quicker build than the Android app.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Eat, drink, and be merry - &lt;/b&gt;Celebrate the most wonderful time of the year with family and friends.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Put the needle on the record - &lt;/b&gt;Put on some headphones, lay on the floor, and enjoy my record collection.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#34;Take a look, it&#39;s in a book...&#34; - &lt;/b&gt;Decide which book I want to read next and spend some time turning pages.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>