<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Indiana Jones on Andy Dyer</title>
    <link>http://andydyer.org/categories/indiana-jones/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Indiana Jones on Andy Dyer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2015 Copyright Andy Dyer</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://andydyer.org/categories/indiana-jones/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The Flying Tomato</title>
      <link>http://andydyer.org/blog/2008/06/02/the-flying-tomato/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://andydyer.org/blog/2008/06/02/the-flying-tomato/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#39;post&#39;&gt;
&lt;a onblur=&#34;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&#34; href=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_Qj61m7RNFOI/SEQN-XVozdI/AAAAAAAAACU/XwQJUNJAscM/s1600-h/080414_park_3084_Fitlow.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;margin: 0px auto 10px; display: block; text-align: center; cursor: pointer;&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/_Qj61m7RNFOI/SEQN-XVozdI/AAAAAAAAACU/XwQJUNJAscM/s320/080414_park_3084_Fitlow.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; id=&#34;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5207302434214956498&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Yes, it&#39;s been over a week yet again since my last post.  If I actually had some readers, this would be a bad thing.  But since I don&#39;t, I guess it doesn&#39;t really matter much.  If anyone does read this drivel, please leave a comment so I can feel good about myself.  Actually, I don&#39;t need anyone to make me feel good about myself, but it would be nice to know you&#39;re reading this.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I, like hundreds of other people yesterday ventured out to Bayou Park for the grand opening of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.houstontx.gov/parks/lee-joepark.html&#34;&gt;Lee and Joe Jamail Skate Park&lt;/a&gt;.  For those of you who haven&#39;t been following its construction, this is a FREE public skate park just outside of downtown.  I dabbled in skateboarding back in 6th &amp;amp; 7th grade and still hop on my board from time to time to ride back and forth like I&#39;m cool.  I really feel like the old guy at the skate park, but the kids don&#39;t seem to mind and I try to stay out of their way.  I didn&#39;t skate yesterday, and instead joined the crowd around the side of the &#34;expert&#34; bowl.  We were treated to demos by some of the top pro skaters, most of whom I didn&#39;t recognize since I followed the sport much more closely &#34;back in the day&#34;.  But none other than &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shaun_White&#34;&gt;Shaun White (Olympic gold medal snowboarder, aka The Flying Tomato)&lt;/a&gt; was there only on a skateboard.  I felt very privileged to see him in action.  Awesome!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In other news, Jamie and I saw the Old 97&#39;s at Meridian on Friday.  They played a bunch of songs from their new album.  There was even a wedding proposal on stage during the sugary sweet &#34;Question&#34;.  I&#39;m liking their new album more and more each time I listen to it.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I also saw the new &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0367882/&#34;&gt;Indiana Jones movie&lt;/a&gt; over the weekend.  It fit nicely with the others and seemed to prepare Shia LaBeouf to take on the role of Indy in the next movie.  I guess we&#39;ll see.  My only beef with the movie was the odd ending, but it is George Lucas, after all.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I finally managed to try some of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.southernstarbrewery.com/&#34;&gt;Southern Star Brewing&#39;&lt;/a&gt;s beer at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.beerknurd.com/&#34;&gt;The Flying Saucer&lt;/a&gt; over the weekend.  Southern Star is a new brewery up near Conroe that was started by a guy I know from my homebrew club and one of his friends.  I tried their &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.southernstarbrewery.com/SSBBeers.asp&#34;&gt;Pine Belt Pale Ale&lt;/a&gt; and really liked it.  Hop nectar, for sure.  Good luck, guys!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Back to work...&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>