<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>He Man on </title>
    <link>http://andydyer.org/categories/he-man/</link>
    <description>Recent content in He Man on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2015 Copyright Andy Dyer</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://andydyer.org/categories/he-man/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on 30</title>
      <link>http://andydyer.org/blog/2008/05/07/thoughts-on-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://andydyer.org/blog/2008/05/07/thoughts-on-30/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#39;post&#39;&gt;
As I&#39;m staring down 30 (tomorrow at 7:01 pm Central to be exact) I should probably blog about how awful it is, but now that it&#39;s inevitable, I really don&#39;t think it&#39;s all that scary. I pretty much act like I&#39;m six as often as I can. I&#39;ve worn one of my favorite t-shirts, a He-Man ringer, for years. I just recently picked up a &#39;Vote Optimus 08&#39; Transformers t-shirt, too. Yep, still very much a kid. But along the way, I have learned a few things.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The meaning of life? Enjoy it.  That&#39;s all.  If there&#39;s something in your life keeping you from doing that, get rid of it.  Whether it&#39;s a job you dread or people you despise, do what you can to change the situation.  An obvious exception is family.  All you can do is try to get along with them.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Keeping up with the Joneses? An utter waste of time. If your existence is so hollow that you think material possessions are a substitute for living, figure out who you are and quit comparing yourself to others.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Music can heal all wounds.  It&#39;s a cure-all for any bad mood and the perfect complement to any good one.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;What other people think about you is irrelevant.  Be yourself regardless of what others think.  True happiness comes from being surrounded by people who like you for who you are, not for living up to some ideal the shallow people try to hold you to.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I&#39;ll add to this as I think of things, but I&#39;d better get to bed.  I need to rest up for what will most likely be a late night of celebrating.  Jamie &amp;amp; I are meeting some friends for dinner and drinks.  And I&#39;m planning on taking Friday off so I won&#39;t be holding anything back.&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>