<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>3500 Calories Is About 23 Beers on </title>
    <link>http://andydyer.org/categories/3500-calories-is-about-23-beers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 3500 Calories Is About 23 Beers on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2015 Copyright Andy Dyer</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://andydyer.org/categories/3500-calories-is-about-23-beers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>My Epic 17 Mile Run &amp; Other Moderately Fascinating Stuff</title>
      <link>http://andydyer.org/blog/2008/07/20/my-epic-17-mile-run--other-moderately-fascinating-stuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://andydyer.org/blog/2008/07/20/my-epic-17-mile-run--other-moderately-fascinating-stuff/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#39;post&#39;&gt;
I haven&#39;t blogged for about three weeks!  While I have the occasional reader, I don&#39;t think anyone&#39;s had to deal with a huge hole in their lives as a result of my absence.  I could blame it on the heat or the fact that we&#39;re now more than halfway through the year and I&#39;ve taken a total of one day of vacation so far.  But I guess I don&#39;t have any real reason other than I just didn&#39;t feel like it.  So what have I been up to?  Mainly, I&#39;ve been doing the work thing, going to concerts, trying to stay on my marathon training plan, and hanging out with Jamie.  (Incidentally, the optional comma before the &#34;and&#34; is known an &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Oxford_comma&#34;&gt;oxford comma&lt;/a&gt; and is also the name of a bad ass &lt;a href=&#34;http://youtube.com/watch?v=P_i1xk07o4g&#34;&gt;Vampire Weekend song&lt;/a&gt;...)&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;I guess I&#39;ll start with the concerts.  I saw &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.myspace.com/harryandthepotters&#34;&gt;Harry and the Potters&lt;/a&gt; @ Walter&#39;s on July 8.  If you&#39;re a fan of the Harry Potter books and haven&#39;t heard of this band, check them out!  All of their songs are (loosely) based on the books and they are hilarious!  Here&#39;s a video I took of &#34;The Weasel&#34;.  That&#39;s a guy in a squid costume jumping on stage to play the drums:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;object height=&#34;344&#34; width=&#34;425&#34;&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;movie&#34; value=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/v/nNOpIWn6iFI&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1&#34;&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowFullScreen&#34; value=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;embed src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/v/nNOpIWn6iFI&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1&#34; type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; height=&#34;344&#34; width=&#34;425&#34;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;This past Friday, we saw &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.myspace.com/officialtillyandthewall&#34;&gt;Tilly and the Wall&lt;/a&gt; play at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.engineroomlive.com/&#34;&gt;Engine Room&lt;/a&gt;.  Jamie is a big fan and while I&#39;ve heard a few of their albums, I really like their latest, &#34;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/o-Tilly-Wall/dp/B0017V7HCK/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=music&amp;amp;qid=1216593115&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;O&lt;/a&gt;&#34;.  Before this album, their percussion consisted of a &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tap_dancing&#34;&gt;tap dancer&lt;/a&gt;.  Yep, the only indie rock band I know of that has a tap dancer.  With &#34;O&#34;, they added a drummer to reinforce the tap dancing.  Here&#39;s the song they opened with, &#34;Too Excited&#34;:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;object height=&#34;344&#34; width=&#34;425&#34;&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;movie&#34; value=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/v/Fli6mWNuceY&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1&#34;&gt;&lt;param name=&#34;allowFullScreen&#34; value=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;embed src=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/v/Fli6mWNuceY&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;fs=1&#34; type=&#34;application/x-shockwave-flash&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; height=&#34;344&#34; width=&#34;425&#34;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;A local band called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.myspace.com/thewildmoccasins&#34;&gt;Wild Moccasins&lt;/a&gt; opened for Tilly.  Like the Young Mammals, this band is another set of whippersnappers with buckets of talent.  Who knew Houston had music of this caliber?  I thought all we had given to the music world was &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=sizzurp&#34;&gt;sizzurp&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grill_%28jewelry%29&#34;&gt;grills&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mike_Jones_%28rapper%29&#34;&gt;Mike Jones&#39; phone number&lt;/a&gt; ad nauseum.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;My running has been going well.  A couple weeks ago, Jamie and I set out midday for a 14 mile run in the Bayou Park/Memorial Park area.  The heat was almost unbearable, but I did manage to finish.  Jamie, being a bit more sane, cut her run short and logged eight miles.  We decided that we would start our long run early this morning, so we set out around 6:45 am.  We ran from my place to Terry Hershey park and ran through the park for a bit before turning around to head back.  I did 17 miles in three hours and 13 minutes.  Jamie turned around at mile seven so she did 14 miles.  Overall, I felt pretty good, especially considering that I burned 3500 calories (that&#39;s a pound!) along the way.  After the run, I ate the first of many post-run meals and took a well deserved nap.  And now, I&#39;m heading to the fridge for some well deserved beer...&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>